I have uh spent about the last 14 years
with the current organization in
credential on five different countries,
six different jobs but all within the
credential family. There's no other
market like Vietnam at the moment as far
as insurance is concerned. [music]
>> The number of then who turn over their
job is quite high expose a lot of stress
[music]
>> customer and marketing you know and
they're very loud. I don't agree by the
way with that observation. It's easy to
point fingers and to say that oh you
know the new generation is hard to work
with. I wouldn't say relaxed, but I
would say stressfree. No, no problem in
life can be so big that you can't deal
[music] with it, right? Credential being
the market leader and be the role model
for the industry. I would say that if
you're someone looking to apply, the
perfect time and the best time.
>> First of all, a warm welcome to all of
our audience who was following Vietnam
assurance. My name is twing hog ass
series title first of all and this is
the podcast where I can interview
managers and senior leader in the
insurance and financial industry and
through those conversations hopefully
that you guys the audience can gain
different perspective especially among
the world changes nowaday
please welcome our special guest he's
the one who have been working with
potential for more than 14 years in
different countries and the topic of
today is going about empowering the next
generations in the new era. Please
welcome Mr. Mananish Gubanis. He's the
chief of strategy and transformations
officers and also interim CCMO at BVA.
Hi [snorts] Manish, thank you so much
for joining us today and for the
beginning may you introduce a bit about
yourself. Thank you for having me here
Lynn and I'm excited to be here, excited
to share a little bit about my journey
about leadership and about being a part
of this very exciting industry. I come
from India. I have uh spent about the
last 14 years with the current
organization in credential. I have moved
AC around five different countries, six
different jobs but all within the
credential family. So while I've got the
stability of being in one organization,
I also have excitement every two or
three years in landing a new job or a
new market which keeps me on my toes and
keeps me very excited.
>> Wow. So including your experience in
other countries 14 years in credential
to me that number is very impressive.
What make you stay so long in the
organization? Well, you know, sometimes
when you're enjoying what you do, uh,
time passes quickly. You don't really
feel that you've spent 14 years in the
organization. Especially in my situation
because I my personal philosophy and
moto in life is to be a lifelong
learner. I like to try different things.
I like to experiment and take on new
roles, take on new challenges. And like
I said, uh, I've been in five different
countries uh, with credential group and
six different jobs. So every two or
three years I'm trying something new. Um
being true to my philosophy of being a
lifelong learner and so it's not really
felt like 14 years. It's felt like time
has gone by very quickly and every
opportunity and every role has been an
exciting venture.
>> So what exactly is the six different job
you may share with us?
>> Sure. Sure. Well when I first started my
career with credential uh I was in
India. I looked after their shared
services uh consulting internal
consulting and knowledge capability. Uh
it was a team of about 80 people looking
at offering
uh value added services on research,
internal consulting, data analytics,
actuarial science, knowledge management.
uh so it was a leadership role but one
that involved uh looking after many many
knowledge based teams and providing
services and support internally to
credential group that was my first job
and then I moved to the UK uh I was
looking after strategy for the
credential UK market again my my first
international role in a different market
outside India uh very regulated very
mature market but that also taught me
about how we manage business and we run
large businesses within the context of
mature markets. Then I moved to
Singapore. In my third role, I was also
head of strategy for Prodential
Singapore. So a lot of excitement, a lot
of energy and in a way it was a second
hub for the Proredential Asia uh region.
So got exposure to number of uh number
of different aspects of the market but
also the regional side of the business.
My fourth role was uh in a small market
uh like Lao. I was a country head for a
small business. uh it was a small but
growing business and uh it was
culturally a very different market to
what I had seen before in Singapore and
UK as you can imagine and my fifth role
is now here in Vietnam looking after
strategy and transformation as the chief
strategy and transformation officer but
also I've taken on an interim role
additional role as chief customer and
marketing officer. So as I shared with
you earlier Lynn, it keeps getting uh
more and more challenging but in a good
way
>> and actually what is the difference
between the insurance industry in
different countries and how it compared
to Vietnam?
>> Uh anyone who is familiar with the
insurance industry in Vietnam will tell
you that this is one of the most
exciting changes and uh transformation
that's happening in the industry right
now. uh for the first two decades from
early 2000s when we started the business
here in Vietnam to about 2020 pre-COVID
uh I would say hyperrowth market uh
because insurance penetration was very
low and uh as the familiarity and
awareness became stronger consumer
demand uh increased very very fast and
so we were one of the first private
insurers in the market and we benefited
as a result of leading that uh leading
that industry but
in every in every market that we've been
in other markets you know whether it's
Asia, Europe, Africa we've seen that
there comes a time when um the business
and the regulator decides to steady the
industry by bringing in important and
necessary changes whether it's around
being customercentric whether it's
around the right products whe whether
it's around pricing sales practices is
so Vietnam has been going through those
changes now in the last three or four
years and rightfully so the regulator
has brought in a lot of important
changes and we are all navigating the
whole industry is navigating those
changes and going through our own
transformation journeys so we are in
that moment it's very exciting there's
no other market like Vietnam at the
moment as far as insurance is concerned
and it's a great opportunity to be here
>> can you share like a changes from the
regulations that you think is going to
be the great changes for the Vietnam
insurance industry.
>> Sure. I think one of the biggest changes
that is coming in for us is how we sell.
>> Uh how we sell and the process of
selling historically has been offering
products you know um and talking about
the products to uh educate customers.
But we we have to change change that
around completely. Now we have to talk
about customer needs first. We have to
talk about customer behavior first. We
have to talk about where where are they
in their life stage and what what really
are their needs and uh and their
requirements and if we feel and as as a
distribution sales staff if they feel
that there is a genuine need for
offering life insurance then they start
talking about the concept. So the whole
um sales pitch if I can call it that has
changed from being more pro from being
product ccentric to more customer
ccentric and understanding life stage
understanding needs understanding
behaviors understanding requirements and
then talking about how the product fits
into that
>> atential you guys have the core value we
pursues our entrepreneur spirit can you
explain that in your way
>> sure well like I said Lynn I mean we are
in a very exciting transformative
journey right for not just as credential
but as as an industry and as we look to
navigate through all these changes and
almost enter
insurance 2.0 right for the Vietnam
market 1.0 being the first 20 years 2.0
maybe being the next 20 years. There are
a lot of opportunities for companies to
innovate. Not just innovate in the form
of offering new products, but innovate
in terms of how we sell, innovate in
terms of how we market the proposition,
innovate in terms of how we uh
incentivize, how we uh recognize both
our internal staff and our large
distribution force. So across the value
chain and across the business model
there are opportunities to do things
differently and that's where the
entrepreneurial spirit comes in. So one
of the things we tell our staff
internally that as we're going through
this transformation think of this as
your own small business. It's not a
small business. It's a very large
business. But if they actually apply the
mentality of this is my own business.
This is my family business or this is my
small business. They they we realize
that there are plenty of opportunities
to innovate. So what about uphold high
standards principle? So look Lynn I mean
the reason why some of these changes
have also come about uh both from the
industry and from the regulation is
because somewhere the industry perhaps
was not living to the same professional
standards that was expected from
financial services as a sector and so
credential being the market leader uh
and one of the largest insurance
companies u we have a responsibility to
lead the way and to to professionalize
this industry uh and when We talk about
upholding high standards as one of our
core values.
We want to practice that on a in a
day-to-day basis. So how the employees
talk about uh insurance, how the
employees conduct themselves in office,
how we manage um ethical practices, how
our salesforce sells to existing
customers and new customers, how we
reward, how we compensate, all of these
aspects, we can raise the bar and that's
why it's really important particularly
in the context of this turnaround to
uphold high standards. And as as
credential, we want to lead the way in
the industry on that.
and be the role model for the industry.
>> When you mention like we keep raising
the bar, I just wonder it means that
it's also expose a lot of stress. How
can you handle with stress
>> individually as leaders as members of
the management team? I think it comes
down to your personal choice. You know,
hold your calm, hold your nerves in in
points of stress. But often you have to
look at the northstar. And for me, one
of the things that I do is I try to uh
manage my energy more than managing my
time. And often it's a misunderstood
and um it's a concept that's not used in
a in in in a powerful way that it should
be. Uh that if you actually if you're
actually able to manage your energy
better, you automatically start to
manage your time better. So I I try to
use that principle as much as possible
to deal with personal stress. And after
being the CCMO another role, how can you
handle stress? Is it different before
and after being promoted?
>> Generally, as a person, I've I've been
brought up to be a calm, collected,
patient,
uh I wouldn't say relaxed, but I would
say stressfree, right? And when there
are moments of high stress like I said
you know you I consciously focus on
managing my energy right which in turn
helps me manage my time and you know
when I have downtimes over the weekend
you know I try to make sure that I'm
spending quality time with family I love
sport so I I I want to uh use my time as
much as possible to continue to practice
you know my sports whether it's tennis
or whether it's golf or whether it's any
new sport that I pick up. I've also
started to learn the piano a little bit
with my with my daughter. My daughter is
eight years old. So, we we learn the
piano together. We have a we have a
Vietnamese teacher who comes in every
weekend and he teaches the piano. So,
it's calming and it's soothing. You
know, at the same time, we spend some
good bonding time as family.
>> How can you recognize when stress come
in? You know, normally uh if you look at
the science and the biology of it,
right, you would see that uh
uh your body will start to source some
reactions, right? You would have to you
would probably start having a higher
heartbeat. You would start to feel a
little bit nervous. You'd start to
sweat. You know, your
uh your eyelids and your expressions
might change. So, sometimes you know it
when that happens. I think it's very
intuitive. Everyone has their own
personal reactions. So it's not
difficult for people to gauge. Uh but
what you do with it is what is more
important. How you cope with it and how
you manage that is most important. And
for me one of the things that I exercise
is
it can't be so big right that life will
come to a standstill. We we we'll
definitely find a way to deal with it
and move on right no problem in life can
be so big that you can't deal with it
right. So I just keep look at the bigger
picture a little phil philosophical in a
way but look at the bigger picture and
then it's much easier to move on. So
manish right now you are at the two
positions one is strategy department and
second one is customer and marketing uh
department what is the difference
between personality of employee in each
department
>> you know uh there is no fixed uh you
know rule of thumb here right uh but I
can tell you generally uh candidates
that we have in strategy team are people
who enjoy working with data people who
are very analytical in nature. Uh people
who like to constantly learn about new
trends in the market and like to uh
predict you know where the industry or
the sector might be headed in the next
few years. So if you have those kind of
skills then often you'll find the
strategy work quite exciting. Um whereas
people in customer and marketing
particularly marketing would be the ones
who are very creative. Um the ones who
are always you know always thinking out
of the box, the ones who are always
thinking about how can we make our brand
and how can we make our proposition uh a
lot more appealing to to new customer
segments to evolving customer needs. So
they are the ones who would be quite
energetic, quite creative, thinking out
of the box um you know and they're very
loud in in a good way in a good way. So
uh so I think it it is slightly
different profiles uh typically but uh
but there may be exceptions to it right
and there's no there's no fixed
guideline on this.
>> So if you can choose are you an
analytical or like creative person.
>> Yeah I I am an analytical I'm more of an
analytical person than a creative
person. I mean this is more because of
my training and my years of working in
strategy and consulting. So this this is
it's it's the skills that I've learned.
But having said that, I love to be
around creative people because one is
what I can offer and what I can share.
Uh being analytical or having a
strategic mindset, but two is what I can
learn from others, right? And then
having that creative uh juices around
you like I said earlier makes you feel
so energized gives you ideas that you
can really really leverage uh in in your
in your different roles in the
organization. So I'm I'm I'm blessed to
be surrounded by both types of skill
sets.
>> Okay. So um if you are analytical
persons how can you harmonize and then
lead creative people?
>> Right.
>> Right. So look, you don't need to be an
expert in everything, right? Uh
sometimes it's about leveraging and
harnessing the strength
and the expertise of people around you.
So we have to complement each other,
right? Where we need a lot of creative a
lot of the out of the box thinking. My
job is to create an environment and
create an atmosphere where we can just
let the ideas flow, right? And I'm an
analytical enough to know that that I
need to exercise the free flowing you
know ideas the free spirit thinking uh
in the team. So we try and create that
environment we try and create that
atmosphere.
Once we have uh whole bunch of ideas
that's the time when you start to have
to be structured
right that's when you need to exercise
some discipline some structure some
analysis on okay now how do you uh
filter these ideas how do you prioritize
these ideas so that's when you can start
to bring some of the skill sets that
I've learned in the past right so you
need to find a way to make both skill
sets work together and I think it's
actually great that this complimentary
to each other and you know We have we
have a very special place for both these
skill sets in the organization
particularly in the teams that I manage.
>> Okay. What you mentioned about
environment may you share about the
environment in prudential how was this
look like? Is this an open communication
and people can speak up during the
meeting?
>> You know uh this is something I'm
actually very proud of. The one of the
reasons why I have been in this
organization for as long as I've been uh
14 years is because working in this
business, working in this organization
and different markets, right? Whether
it's Singapore or whether it's London or
whether it's Hong Kong, whether it's
Vietnam or smaller markets, the
consistent fabric that runs across his
organization is this very open-minded,
transparent and positive culture.
Right? Right? We have so many employees
in the organization who have been around
for so long because they connect with
that culture. And so Vietnam is no
different. So we have a very open, very
transparent, very honest culture. Um we
have an environment where our
communication platforms, our channels
are open. uh at any point of time anyone
who who has started as a management
traininee in the organization can reach
out to the CEO express and share ideas
and we do it typically through our
technology platform. So we use Microsoft
Teams. Um so we you know that channel is
open. There is no restriction. There is
open communication. There are regular
engagements, town halls. Uh and this is
not something new and unique to
Credential, right? A lot of
multinational companies, a lot of
companies that care about building
engagement and the right culture in the
organization, they do it. But I would
say within credential what I have seen
is people are very warm, very friendly,
very welcoming uh to new employees and
it's not you know we we really care. We
really care uh you know when we bring in
new employees we really care about
making sure that they are on boarded
well they're taken good care of uh and
they're successful in the organization.
So something that I'm actually genuinely
quite proud of and one of the reasons
I've been here for so long. Let's talk
about your leadership style working in
credential for 14 years. How it changed
over years?
>> It's a very good question because it has
changed and it should change right
because as you as you uh as you evolve
as a professional you go through
different experiences you go through
different leadership journeys
um you will learn and adapt. For me when
I started as a young professional as a I
would say a manager or a senior manager
I was uh quite task oriented. I was
quite focused on the job at hand. I was
quite focused on deliverables, deadlines
um and producing results of very high
quality. Uh so I was very focused on
that. uh over the years you know while I
still try to keep higher standards of
quality uh in whatever I do one of the
things that has evolved is the
leadership style of being task oriented
uh to being a lot more empathy oriented
and this has evolved because over time
I've also had the opportunity to speak
to so many people to so many young
people who join us and to really
understand that they all come from very
different backgrounds around very
different experiences. They're all going
through very different stresses and
emotions in life and work is one part of
it but is not the only thing in their
life. So if you really want to get the
best out of them, it's important to
understand what else are they really
going through and what can we help and
support with in order for them to be the
most productive and the best version of
themselves at work.
>> Thank you manage for your sharing and
now we move to the second part of our
podcast. It's gonna be about the culture
of innovations and the way potential
Vietnam empower the young generations.
>> How many member in your team?
>> My strategy and transformation team is
about 15 people.
Uh the customer and marketing team in
total is about 80 people. So all in all
it's about into two teams are about 100
people.
>> What about the average edge? I'd say the
it's both the teams and and and
generally credential Vietnam is a very
young profile. So I would think that the
the average age for at least my teams is
you know around 30 in in that range. I I
have a lot of uh I have a lot of team
members who are uh you know Gen Z so who
would be in their early 20s mid20s I
have some who who would be about 10 15
years experience in the industry so
would be you know about mid-30s or so
but on the on the whole the average age
is quite young and it's a very energetic
and a vibrant team.
>> So from your experience what is your
experience working with the Zenzi?
>> Ah I love it. I absolutely love it. I uh
you know they bring uh the amount of
energy and youth and exuberance
um you know creative thinking, fresh
energy that uh actually can be quite
infectious can be quite infectious and
can you know make uh you know some of
the more experienced and tenure members
like myself feel very vibrant, very
energetic and very active. Right? So, so
they help me uh you know, they help me
think like a youth. They help me think
uh more creatively and more importantly,
you know, I learn a lot from them. Even
though life insurance is typically
bought by people who have, you know,
started work or who have, you know, uh
who have recently married or who have
kids, the younger children in the house
are in influencing the decisions a lot.
So our ability to connect with the
overall family is important. And what I
constantly and daily learning from our
team members, the Gen Z team members is
what kind of marketing, what kind of
social media reach, what kind of
communication is required to really
connect with your audience at a much
more deeper level. And these methods are
very different to what I was used to
right 15 20 years back because it's
changed so much. And uh as you sharing I
see that you will share on the very
positive side on working with Zenzi. But
according to one of the LinkedIn
research actually that the number of
Zenzee who turn over their job and then
also show the ego in working environment
is quite high and I would say that it is
going to be not really positive side of
working with Zenzi. Have you ever facing
with that problem and how you deal with
that? I don't agree by the way with that
observation and I don't agree with the
findings because I feel somewhere if you
have people in the company and by the
way this doesn't have to be just Gen Z
right it could be any generation
if they are
feeling disengaged
feeling dis you know disenfranchised
and if they are feeling that uh they're
not finding that same level of
excitement and energy
It's probably something that the
management and the company needs to fix
first, right? It's easy to point fingers
and to say that oh, you know, the new
generation is hard to work with, but we
know that they are all very ambitious.
They all creative. They want to make a
difference and in fact they bring some
qualities that you know some of the
older I would say uh you know working
profile did not have. They care a lot
more about the environment. They care
about sustainability. They want to join
companies which bring a purpose, which
have a passion to make a difference and
they connect with those things. Right?
So there's a lot of qualities that you
can really really harness and in in that
construct if you're not able to keep the
workforce engaged or keep them excited
or motivated or giving them new
challenges then I think it's something
that we as management have to fix first
regardless of generation whether it's
Gen Z, Gen X, Gen Y and drive a lot more
positive engagement and so those are the
things for us to work on rather than you
know trying to compartmentalize these
into issues. is related to E generation.
>> So if I'm a new employee and I want to
apply and joining your team, what the
criteria I would need for strategy
department and for your new CCMO role
too?
>> A lot of things are going to change and
the way we see jobs in boxes and in
departments today will not be the same
over the next few years. So my appeal to
people who are
looking to enter the corporate workforce
or looking to be a part of this change
and exciting transformation let's say
for credential would be not to look at
it as boxes but look at it as skills
and people who are more interested to
solve complex business problems exercise
problem solving skills. exercise
judgment, exercise what we call
horizontal skills
are the ones who would actually and and
the ones who are able to adapt and who
have the learning agility are the ones
that who will really succeed in the
future. So I would suggest don't look at
strategy versus you know marketing
customer versus finance versus
operations but look at it as do you have
the learning agility do you have the
problem solving ability to go in in any
of these areas and I would encourage you
to think broad before you start to think
too deep because at the end of the day
if you are a generalist by nature but if
you're able to go deep into specific
areas come out of it go and solve other
problems come out of it go and solve
other problems. That's going to really
make you succeed in this what we call
VAUA world, right? Volatile, uncertain,
complex and ambiguous world and that's
what's going to prepare you for the
future to be successful.
>> Thank you so much again and hopefully
that I can have an update for your
strategy plan and also your new role.
>> Thank you very much Lyn. It was a
pleasure to be here. I hope I could
share with the audience you know how we
think about uh leadership, how we think
about change, how we think about
transformation and how the industry is
really going to be exciting for us going
forward. [snorts]
>> Thank you manage for just sharing.
>> Pleasure to be here. Thank you very
much.
[music]